<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 1.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode
		xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.6" 
		xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
		xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.6 https://knime.org/node/v3.6.xsd" 
		icon="RxnFileReader.png" 
		type="Source">
    <name>Chemical Reactions File Reader</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Reads chemical reactions from a file.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
Use this node to read chemical reactions stored on your hard drive.
 Different file formats are supported. These include, but are not limited to,
 Chemical Markup Language (CML) files; a number of Symyx (former MDL) formats -
 rxn, rdf; SMILES/SMIRKS; etc. See
 http://www.chemaxon.com/marvin/help/formats/formats.html for an extensive list.
 		</intro>
        
        <option name="Select file(s)">
 Use the Add and Remove buttons to add to the list of files to process. Changing the list will automatically tigger a scan in either shallow or deep mode.
        </option>
        
        <option name="Scan Depth">
 	Shallow scan is the first 10 records of each file, whilst a deep scan will scan each file completely for properties.
        </option>
        
        <option name="Properties to keep">
All reaction properties found in the first 10 records of the input file are
 presented in the left-hand side list. Use the provided controls to select the
 properties you are interested in. These will be read and stored in the output
 of the node. Note that all properties are treated as strings - in the likely
 case that some or all of the properties are numeric you may use the 
 "String To Number" node. The "String To Number" node is part of the default 
 KNIME installation and may be found under the category
 "Data Manipulation | Column".
        </option>
        
        <option name="Output options -> General -> Aromatize molecules">
Select this option if you want the chemical structures which constitute the
 reaction to be aromatized using the default Chemaxon algorithm. Reccomended.
        </option>
        
        <option name="Output options -> Additional columns">
In addition to the "native" Chemaxon RxnMolecule object a number of columns 
 containing different text-based representations of the read reactions can be
 created as well. These are useful when an interaction with another
 chemoinformatics package is needed. For example, to use this reader with the
 CDK library (since it supports much more file formats) you can output an RDF 
 column which can than be processed by CDK.
        </option>
        
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <outPort index="0" name="Read Reactions Output">
The read chemical reactions are output here. A column containing Chemaxon
 RxnMolecule objects is always present. Depending on the configuration, a number
 of other columns - representing the read reactions in another string-based
 format or containing properties read from the input file - may be present as
 well.
 		</outPort>
 		<outPort index="1" name="Failed to Read Reactions Output">
The  chemical reactions that failed to read are output here. 
 		</outPort>
    </ports>    
    
    <views>
        <view index="0" name="Read Reactions">View the read reactions with MarvinView</view>
    </views>
</knimeNode>
